It's no secret that our society has a digital device problem. Ninety-two percent of Americans own a smartphone. Research has found that we are more connected than ever before and yet feel more isolated, more lonely, more depressed than ever before. How is that possible?
Social scientists call this a collective action problem. We all agree that these devices are having a detrimental impact on our mental health, and yet it feels virtually impossible to withdraw from these devices because they are so interconnected in our lives. So what can we do?
Well, good morning. Wonderful to see all of you this morning. If we haven't had the privilege of meeting yet,
my name is Ryan, and I am privileged to be one of the pastors here. And we are in week three of a four-week series on digital detox and the influence of modern technology on our spiritual lives.
And attendance is looking light. So I don't know if that means a lot of people are traveling for the summertime or you guys are sick of talking about your phones,
but we're in the homestretch. We're getting close. And as a part of this series, we're inviting you all to participate in a 28-day digital detox.
You guys have heard, most of you have heard this already. There's an insert in your bulletin that can help you unpack some of the ways some of us are participating in this.
And again, we've said this from the beginning, we are not anti-tech, but we do acknowledge over the past two weeks,
we've talked about the fact that technology can be a very effective tool in conforming us into the patterns of this world.
And it also amplifies the voice. Last week we talked about it amplifying the voice of thieves and robbers who seek to steal, kill, and destroy our lives,
over and above the voice of the Good Shepherd who offers us life and life more abundantly.
So yeah, that's where we've been, and we are in the homestretch looking forward to that.
I do want to do one more shameless plug for Team Night. We have some big news that we're going to be announcing at Team Night,
and we like to give big news to our volunteers and our members first. And so I just want you to know that's coming.
I know not all of you can make it, but if you can, please try. And I'd love for that to happen.
Okay, let's pray. Holy Spirit, we just submit this to you.
Submit this time to you moving forward. Pray that you would just be at work through everything that happens under this roof this morning,
that you would have your way, that you would prepare our hearts, that you would speak through your word
and through other believers to open our eyes to see where you're at work.
Ask us questions that we don't want to be asked. Challenge us where we don't want to be challenged.
And ultimately, God, I pray that this time together would be a step forward in our surrendered obedience to you.
For those that are in here that don't yet know you, that are just kind of kicking the tires of Christianity and are curious about your word,
I pray that this would be a really clear proclamation of who they are, who they were made to be, and what you're inviting them into moving forward.
I pray all of this in Jesus' name. Amen.
We're going to be in Genesis 1 through 3. So if you want to turn there, it shouldn't be hard to find. If you're new to the Bible, it's at the very beginning.
So we're making it easy for you this morning. As you're turning there, I would love to ask you all a question.
Have any of you ever ignored your GPS because you were convinced that you knew a better way?
All right. Now, do me a favor. Leave your hand up if that had ever backfired on you.
Okay. Some of you are smarter than the GPS than others. I remember a while back, our in-laws were coming to visit us.
We knew their kind of estimated time of arrival. And so when time was getting close for them to show up, we have some location sharing.
And so my wife checked her sister's location, and they were still about an hour and a half away, which was not their ETA.
And so Marissa texted her sister, and her sister is very funny.
And so she was in the backseat with mom and dad in the front seat, and she gave a hilarious commentary.
I don't remember all the specifics, but it was something like the GPS was trying to take them a different way than they normally go.
And so they just decided to go the way they normally go. They ran into, I think it was traffic, and then they got so stuck in traffic that they tried to, again, ignore the rerouting of the GPS
and get back to the original route. And when they got back to the original route, there was an accident, and then at that point, it was just all, you know, the wheels were off, quite literally.
And so it was just a wild time. And I realized the issue for them wasn't the destination. The destination had not changed, but it was the guide that they were putting their trust in.
And then having a GPS that had moment-by-moment connection to satellite and updates with traffic and construction and all the things to like an old-school Atlas navigation.
Now, I realized that if you were here for last week's message, an opening illustration about trusting technology, slightly ironic on my part. I get that.
But I think it's a helpful picture for our passage this morning, because last week we talked about this passage in John 10,
where there are thieves and robbers who come to us with a voice that is opposite of the voice of the Good Shepherd.
And these voices lead to our lives being stolen and ultimately led astray from where God wants us to.
And we said that at the end of the day that there are lots of thieves and robbers, but all of those voices can be traced back to the original voice of the thief in the garden.
And today what we're going to do is we're going to look at that origin story of the original voice of the thief so that we can better understand how our screens and our devices are still amplifying that voice in our lives regularly.
And I think what we're going to see is that the destination for us as human beings, from the very beginning, the destination has not changed.
We are still going in the same direction. We are still trying to achieve the thing that God made us to achieve.
But the guide in which we put our trust in to accomplish those things has changed.
So let's read in Genesis chapter 1, starting in verse 26.
We're going to hop around to a couple of different places.
Genesis 1, starting in verse 26, it says, "Then God said, 'Let us make man in our image, after our likeness, and let them have dominion over the fish of the sea,
and over the birds of the heavens, and over the livestock, and over all the earth, and over every creeping thing that creeps on the earth.
So God created man in his own image. In the image of God, he created them male and female, he created them.
And God blessed them, and God said to them, 'Be fruitful and multiply, fill the earth and subdue it.
Have dominion over the fish of the sea, and over the birds of the heavens, and over every living thing that moves on earth.'"
We skip to chapter 2, verse 15, that says, "The Lord God took the man and put him in the Garden of Eden to work it and keep it."
And so, from the very beginning, we get this idea of the destination that God created humanity for.
At the very beginning, God lays out his intended destination for us as humans, that we are created in his image.
We are given dominion over his creation. This is, from the beginning, all of us, this is our identity and our calling.
Our identity is image bearers of the Creator God, and our calling is to have dominion over creation.
God plants a garden of abundance for them, and he gives them the responsibility and the authority to expand the goodness of Eden across the rest of the world.
The rest of the world was full of potential, but not yet like Eden, and so God commissions and sets apart these image bearers who would image him to the rest of creation.
They would expand Eden moving forward. The term here that we see in Genesis 2:15, to work it and keep it, is a phrase that is later used of the priests in the tabernacle.
And so the original calling for humans was to worship God in the way in which we worked throughout creation.
I think that's a really beautiful reminder for those of us that we often shrink down the definition of what worship is.
It becomes this very spiritual term that only happens in certain contexts, but from the beginning, God was inviting us to worship him in our vocation, in our calling.
And so whatever it is that you might do on a regular basis, there are opportunities for you to worship God in what looks like ordinary, everyday tasks.
So our identity, our calling from the very beginning is to image God in the way that we expand Eden throughout creation.
And as we read ahead in the story, we'll see, we've talked about this previously, it becomes clear that even after the fall, even after sin enters the world,
the destination doesn't change. Humans are still worshiping. We are still seeking to create Eden-like abundance in the world around us.
We are still trying to do the thing that we were made for. The destination has not changed.
What has changed is the guide in which we choose to put our trust in to get to that destination, which leads us to the weird death tree.
Okay? Everybody loves the death tree. Genesis 2:15-17.
Again, the Lord God took man and put him in the Garden of Eden to work it and keep it.
And the Lord God commanded the man, saying, "You may surely eat of every tree of the garden,
but of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil you shall not eat, for in the day you eat of it you will surely die."
The Hebrew literally says, "Die, die."
When you eat of it, you will die, die. Not a good tree, apparently, right?
So I don't know about you, and I don't know that I was ever taught this or if I just assumed this,
but for most of my life when reading this text, I came to the assumption or the conclusion or the thought process
that the knowledge of good and evil is a bad thing.
Does anybody else feel like they grew up with that idea, the knowledge of good and evil, bad thing?
Okay. I mean, look at the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, right?
If you eat of it, you will die, die. That seems like a bad thing,
but the more that I've thought about this and looked at it and studied it and been influenced by other people,
I don't think that that's what we are trying to get across in Genesis chapter 2.
This phrase, knowledge of good and evil, is used three other times in the Hebrew Bible,
and all three times it is a positive thing where people who need wisdom are gaining in wisdom, learning wisdom.
It becomes an idea of some adolescent or child or innocent person who doesn't have wisdom and needs wisdom and gets wisdom.
The clearest example in the Scriptures is King Solomon. You guys remember King Solomon, David's son?
What happens to Solomon is he falls asleep and he has a dream and God comes to Solomon and God says,
that you can ask for anything that you want and I will give it to you.
We remember the story? Some of us. Okay. So literally, you can read it in first Kings chapter three, Solomon asks for the knowledge of good and evil.
And God is very pleased. And so I think what we need to get in our minds here is it's not the knowledge of good and evil that is a bad thing.
The knowledge of good and evil is wisdom. It's wisdom that Adam and Eve would need to fulfill their calling.
Wisdom that they had already begun to receive from their creator. Throughout Genesis, we see God declaring things as good.
And then we see God declaring something as not good. He is defining for them what the definition of good and evil is, and he would continue to do so.
We see him walking to them in the garden. That there is this relationship of vulnerability and trust, and that he is giving them what they need.
The wisdom that they need as they need it to accomplish the thing that he created them for.
This is a tree of wisdom, but the problem is, who are we trusting to get our wisdom from?
Which leads us to the origin story of the original thief in Genesis chapter 3.
Let's read it, and then we'll talk about how weird it is. Okay.
"Now, the serpent was more crafty than any other beast of the field that the Lord God had made.
He said to the woman, "Did God actually say, 'You shall not eat of any tree in the garden?'"
And the woman said to the serpent, "We may eat of the fruit of the trees in the garden, but God said, 'You shall not eat of the fruit of the tree that is in the middle of the garden, neither shall you touch it, lest you die-die.'"
Sorry, I really like that. That's so fun.
"But the serpent said to the woman, 'You will not die-die, for God knows that when you eat, your eyes will be opened, and you will be like God,
knowing good and evil.'" So when the woman saw that the tree was good for food, that it was a delight to the eyes,
and that the tree was to be desired to make one wise, she took its fruit and ate.
She also gave some to her husband, who was with her, and he ate. Then the eyes of both of them were opened.
They knew that they were naked, and so they sewed fig leaves together and made themselves loincloths."
All right, can we just be straight up? Talking snake is weird.
And the fact that those of us who grew up in the church pretend that it's not weird is also weird.
We're just like, "Yeah, of course, there's a talking snake at the beginning of creation.
It's supposed to happen. It's normal. It's not normal. It's weird."
And we could literally, we could do a whole sermon or sermon series on the snake and all of the
cultural ideas around it and what it means and why it means. We don't have time to get into that.
I think for now what I want to say is the snake seems to be some type of spiritual being, divine being.
It doesn't, the Hebrew allows for it to not just be wiser than any other beast in the field.
Like, it is a beast that's wiser than the other beast. It just allows it to be just wiser than the other creatures.
And we know from other Scriptures that there are divine beings that exist that are interacting with God.
There's a spiritual realm and a physical realm. We've talked about all of these things in the past.
I don't have time to get into them right now, but for now I will say that the snake seems to be a divine being,
and it also seems to have more wisdom than the other creatures.
And even the way that our translators kind of lead us down a path, it says crafty.
It sounds morally negative. I'm told that the Hebrew is very morally neutral.
It is wisdom that can be used for positive or for negative.
And so we have a wise spiritual being coming to Eve and beginning to question God's wisdom.
So he's using his wisdom in a negative way, and he offers her a shortcut for their intended destination.
He's coming to them. He says, "I know what you were made for. I know what God has created you to be."
The way in which he's giving you the wisdom you need to rule the creation that he's called you to is setting you back.
There's a shortcut that you can take. There's a faster route to get to the destination that God has laid out for you.
He essentially says you can have the thing you'll need to do the thing God made you to do, and you can have it right now.
You don't have to wait for God to teach you wisdom. You can seize it for yourself and immediately become like God.
You can have God's promises apart from God's presence.
And what comes next in my mind is one of the most tragic grammar transitions in all of Scripture.
Because again, up to this point in the Genesis account, God has been the one who is seeing things and defining if they are good or not.
All throughout Genesis 1, God sees it's good. God sees it's good. God sees it's very good.
Then he gets to Adam being alone, and God sees that it's not good. God is the one who is seeing and defining what is good and what is bad.
And what we see in this transition when the serpent comes to Eve and just offers her this idea that she might be able to define wisdom for herself.
Verse 6 says, "The woman saw the tree was good for food."
So all the way out through the text, God is seeing and defining what is good, and now after this hint of this temptation, this discussion, this decision for Adam and Eve to be made, now Eve sees something that God had said wasn't good, and she begins to declare it good in her own eyes.
She begins the process right here and now of trusting her own definition of good and evil apart from God.
Her and Adam both participate in this choice together and the result is immediate death-death, okay? They did indeed die-die.
This is the result. Death doesn't come when they get kicked out of the garden, but it comes the moment that they begin to choose to trust their own wisdom apart from God.
It's important that we know that God does not kill Adam and Eve. The fruit from the tree does not kill Adam and Eve.
It is their decision to take the ability to define good and evil for themselves that kills them.
And as we unpack why that might be, I think it's really important that up to this point, the world is being governed by God's wisdom, and God's wisdom accounts for everyone and everything in creation.
It cultivates mutually beneficial and life-giving morality that benefits everyone equally. God's wisdom is bigger and better than limited human wisdom.
When we take wisdom for ourselves, when we define it for ourselves, it limits the scope and the perspective of that definition of wisdom.
And then what happens immediately, and we see this in the garden, is what I define as good is often at odds with what my neighbor defines as good.
And then we become at odds with one another.
And now we're all defining wisdom for ourselves. We're all defining good and evil for ourselves.
And the immediate result is death. Adam and Eve stopped.
When Adam and Eve stopped viewing vulnerability and mutual partnership as a virtue, death occurred.
They moved from co-submitted partners that are under God's authority in a world full of abundance.
This is their existence, co-submitted partners, both under the defining wisdom of God working together to bring about Eden-like circumstances in the world around them.
They moved from that to autonomous and a fractured partnership in a world where I heard one pastor define it as protective scarcity.
Immediately, the move becomes God is in charge. He's telling us what to do. We're waiting on him. Everything around us looks great.
There's abundance everywhere, and in that moment, everything shrinks down, and all they can think about is how they're going to get what they need for their calling and their identity,
and we are immediately moved from abundance to protective scarcity. It feels like there isn't enough, and it feels like other people are making decisions about what is good and bad for them,
and their decisions about what is good and evil is limiting my potential to get the thing that I need to define what I have as good and evil.
That same pastor who defined protective scarcity, he talked about the image of God as both a noun and a verb, and so what doesn't happen at the fall when we die-die is we don't stop being noun images of God.
God created all humanity, all humankind in His image. We image God. We are noun images of God. The calling and vocation that He put on our lives to worship
and to cultivate Eden-like circumstances, none of that goes away. The destination does not go away, but we now can choose whether we will verb image God or not.
And when we stop being verb images of God, the result is regular death. My overarching point for this morning is this. The fall wasn't humanity choosing evil over good. It was humanity
choosing good apart from God. This is what we see, that the destination doesn't change. Humans are still worshiping. They're still trying to cultivate Eden-like circumstances in the world around them, but they're choosing to do something that is good that God made them for apart from God, and that always leads to death.
If you will allow me, I will read a long quote because I think it summarizes this far better than I could ever say it. Does that sound okay?
All right, you got to put on your focus caps for like the next two slides. Got it? All right.
One author puts it this way, "In Genesis 2 and 3, Adam and Eve's sin is a departure from a relationship of love and trust of their Creator.
The serpent offers them a fake deification, a tragic imitation of a divine nature that they already have.
They are already God's divine image, carrying the divine breath with divine privileges and wisdom.
God has already shown them the difference between good and evil and would continue to guide them in that discernment.
They are the image idols of Creator Yahweh God. The serpent offers them a shot at becoming only like gods.
In apparent, this is where we can't judge their motives. We don't know exactly what was going on in their heart,
but in apparent ignorance or forgetfulness of or in rebellion against their true identity,
they fall prey to the serpent's insinuations that their Creator had deceived them.
The tree that should have proved their discernment between wrongdoing and faithfulness to God
becomes instead a tree that leads to their experience of both evil and lingering good.
In the same way that idolaters become like what they worship, so humans become like leaf-clad trees.
They immediately start to image creation rather than the Creator by putting on clothes of leaves.
They give up the splendor of their Creator, inclining to the voice of the creature,
and are left bereft of the glory that was theirs by rights.
Their action strikes at the heart of their identity, and succumbing to the lie that they need something that they already have,
they annihilate themselves. And so, after sin, there is nothing for it but death.
They do not cease to noun-image God, but they cease to verb-image God, and in doing so, they begin to verb-image creation.
Their choice was like that of trading the all-knowing GPS with constant updates on traffic and construction to the ability of reading an atlas.
The source of wisdom we choose will determine what we image. And so, this is what's happening in the fall,
and this is what is continuing to happen over and over and over again on repeat, is what is the source of wisdom
that we are putting our trust in to get to the destination that God made us for?
To quote Paul, he puts it beautifully. He says it this way in Romans 1,
"For although they knew God, they neither glorified Him as God nor gave thanks to Him.
But their thinking became futile, and their foolish hearts were darkened. Although they claimed to be wise, they became fools and exchanged the glory
of the immortal God for images made to look like mortal human beings and birds and animals and reptiles."
So from the very beginning, we see that God has placed a important calling, an invitation for humanity.
And the crafty serpent comes and gives them an offering that is different, and they choose not to change the destination they are going.
All of us as human beings, we still worship and we still seek to cultivate Eden-like circumstances in the world around us.
But what changed is the guide in which we put our trust in.
Instead of coming to Yahweh and allowing Him to define what is good and evil for us,
we seize that autonomy for ourselves, and we choose to now define good and evil in our own terms.
Now, hopefully by this point, you might be asking yourself,
"What does all of this have to do with screen time and digital detoxing?"
Thank you so much for asking that question,
because that's the question we're going to answer next in my outline. I'm so glad you guys asked.
You guys were thinking that, right? Okay, good.
So again, our destination as humans have not changed.
We are worshipers seeking to cultivate Eden-like circumstances in the world around us,
but our primary guide has changed where we get our wisdom from.
And I don't know if you have noticed this or not, but there is a big gap between our wisdom and God's wisdom.
And so technology becomes one of the biggest accelerators of the human inclination to seize the definition of wisdom for ourselves.
Technology becomes a primary companion for humanity at cultivating Eden-like conditions apart from God.
We see this even as early as Genesis chapter 11 in the Tower of Babel story.
It says, "Now the whole earth had one language and the same words.
And as people migrated from the east, they found a plain in the land of Shinar and settled there.
And they said to one another, "Come, let us make bricks and burn them thoroughly."
And they had bricks for stone and bitumen and mortar.
They said, "Come, let us build ourselves a city and a tower with its top to the heavens, and let us make a name for ourselves, lest we be dispersed over the face of the earth."
And so the Eden decision was to become like God, to seize autonomy and wisdom for ourselves.
And the Babel narrative is that outworking of that decision heightened by human ingenuity and technology.
Right? It's we're going to use the resources and the wisdom that we have to build for ourselves, even like circumstances, apart from God.
And I want to argue that our phones and the applications on them are a pinnacle, the pinnacle of thousands and thousands of years of the Babel inclination.
Over and over again, being developed and refined to leverage technology in a way that closes the gap between us and God.
And I don't get the opportunity to do this very often. And so what I want to do now is I just want to flex my Bible college degree from a very prestigious university that no longer exists.
I love my college. I'm thankful for it, but I'm going to flex on some Bible college.
We're going to talk a couple big theological words that are defining characteristics or attributes of God.
And all of you are familiar with these terms. I am sure the first of which is omniscience, right?
Which means God is all-knowing. Yes, God is all-knowing.
And our phones come to us, and they promise us access to unlimited knowledge at the tap of the finger.
This is Babel-like inclination developed over thousands and thousands of years, trying to close the gap between our wisdom and God's wisdom.
Our phones are promising us the illusion of omniscience, the illusion that we don't need to look to God for defining good and wisdom,
because we can just Google it on our phones right now. God is omnipresent. He's everywhere.
I don't know if you have friends or family members that live outside of the state or outside of the country, but our phones promise us instant access to be anywhere at any time.
Again, there are these false illusions that we are more like God than we realize. Omnipotence. God is all-powerful.
Our phones give us influence and opportunities far beyond our natural limitations. Technology that we have honed over thousands of thousands of years
that give us the illusion that we are more like God than we actually are. God is full of abundance. He created everything and needs nothing.
God's promise almost the same with constant entertainment and instant delivery of anything we could ever want within one to two business days.
It's this technology that is being used by our Babel and Eden-like inclination to seize wisdom from God and to create Eden-like circumstances outside of relationship with God.
The last one is God's eternality, right? God is eternal. He exists outside of time.
And as I was doing some research for this, I came across a really kind of disturbing new organization.
Any of you ever heard of the 2045 initiative?
Okay, good. It's creepy. It's really creepy.
A guy by the name of Dmitry Itskov is a futurist who created the 2045 initiative.
With the stated goal, this is their stated goal, of creating technologies enabling the transfer of an individual's personality to a more advanced non-biological carrier and extending life including to the point of immortality.
So technology put in the hands of noun image bearers who are choosing not to verb image God, who are choosing to seize autonomy and wisdom for themselves.
Technology can become an accelerator of this inclination to create Eden-like circumstances apart from God, and it will not work, but it often gives the illusion that it's working.
Our phones and our tablets and our technology, they are increasingly offering us things that sound suspiciously God-like.
And again, I want to be clear when we said this, and we're going to keep saying it, technology isn't inherently bad.
All of us are aware of tremendous examples of technology being used for good. Some of us have people that are alive today that would not be alive without the modern technology used in medicine, but technology becomes dangerous when it accelerates our avoidance of God, when it becomes our preferred source of wisdom, comfort, identity, and purpose.
This process of accelerating our inclination to define wisdom apart from God is subtly giving us the illusion that we don't need God to experience Eden, and it's slowly killing us.
Our phones and the applications on them, they are giving us the illusion that we can experience Eden-like circumstances apart from God.
And I don't think any well-intended Christian is going to their phone and thinking, "Man, this feels a lot like Eden."
I don't need to spend any time with God or trust Him in any way. It's not happening that obviously, it's happening coercively.
And we're subtly being lulled to sleep with mindless entertainment.
And we're buying the same lie that the serpent gave to Adam and Eve, that you can have what God made you for without God.
But what we have is an awful substitute, a terrible exchange of the glory of the immortal God for created things.
It fractures our relationships, it causes anxiety, it promotes envy and lust, it leads to distraction, outrage, loneliness, and spiritual numbness.
This is the human condition, images of God created to image God and worship Him by cultivating Eden in partnership with Him.
And instead we've seized that definition of wisdom for ourselves, and we've sought to worship creation rather than the Creator.
And then one of the primary questions becomes, "How is it working?"
How is this pursuit working for us to make it more personal? How is it working for you?
And your ability to cultivate Eden-like experiences apart from God.
I think it's so important, if you've been coming to Canvas for any time at all, we've probably revisited the Genesis story 15 times at this point.
And we're going to keep coming back to it over and over again. It's important that we have this story in our minds when we read the New Testament.
Because the gospel is so much more than God is forgiving you of your sins so that you can go to heaven when you die.
When Jesus shows up and when John says the invisible God has become visible, the image of God is here among us, the invitation from Jesus is to opt out of this way of living.
This is what he means when he talks about being born again. You do not have to live as noun images, not verb imaging.
You can die to yourself, and you can be born again to a new way of living.
It's an invitation to begin to relearn a life-giving definition of wisdom from God.
This is what it means when Jesus says, "Follow me." It's an invitation to partner with God in the flesh
and a united family of co-submitted Christ followers. He is reconvening the partnership of Adam and Eve pre-fall
when he brings people from every tribe, language, nation, and tongue together as submitted followers of Jesus
to the wisdom of God. And he's saying, "You people are now a new family
who gets to live according to a new wisdom." Actually, it's not new at all. It is the eternal wisdom
that has existed from the beginning that you have opted out of. You get to opt back into it.
It is a wisdom that leads to Eden-like circumstances for everyone.
This is what Jesus means when he talks about the kingdom of heaven is here. It's now. The kingdom of heaven
spreads across the earth as people are choosing to lay down their old lives
where wisdom is defined by themselves and be born again into a new family
by the power of Jesus who did for us what Adam could not or would not do.
In John chapter 5, Jesus says, "I do nothing except what I see my Father doing."
Jesus is the imperfect embodiment of getting the knowledge of good and evil from God,
of refusing to seize it for himself. This is why Matthew 4 is so important.
When the serpent comes to Jesus, when Satan comes to Jesus in the wilderness
and gives him the temptations of Adam, he's inviting Jesus to make the same decision.
Trade God's wisdom for your own wisdom and get life.
And Jesus refuses to do it. He submits his will to the wisdom of the Father.
He says, "I am the way, the truth, and the life."
This is how we relearn how to be image bearers who image God like we were intended to at the beginning.
We look to Jesus who is the way, the truth, and the life.
Jesus did what Adam failed to do. Adam reaches out his hand to the tree to seize wisdom for himself.
Jesus stretched out his hand upon the tree to submit to the Father's wisdom.
This is what Paul meant in Romans chapter five that we read earlier about being in Adam or being in Christ.
These are our options. We are noun image bearers, but who will we choose to verb image?
Will we verb image Adam, who seizes autonomy for himself, and who starts this pattern of leveraging technology to try and close the gap between our wisdom and God's wisdom?
Or will we submit ourselves to Jesus, who is the image of the invisible God, the firstborn of all creation?
The answer to Genesis three and the point of the digital fast is not to reject technology, it's to relearn trust.
Learning to receive wisdom through surrender to Jesus rather than seizing it for ourselves. Learning to follow the guide to our intended destination instead of insisting we know a better way.
The goal of the detox is to create enough space from our devices so that when we come back to them, we can use them as a tool guided by God's wisdom rather than a tool that accelerates our own.
This becomes for us the key question when we interact with technology is, is our technology being leveraged or used in such a way that allows us to continue to submit to the wisdom of God?
Or is it being subtly or even intentionally used to make us think that our wisdom is working out for ourselves?
I hope and my prayer throughout this series is that we would just have a new, clearer vision for what it looks like, not just with technology, but for everything to be surrendered to the wisdom of God.
Everything that we have authority and autonomy in in our lives, are we submitting it to God or are we seizing it for ourselves?
Because one leads to life and life more abundantly.
Sorry, I had to do it one more time. And one leads to us. Die, die.
Let's pray. Father in heaven,
you are all wise, all powerful, all knowing.
You gave us identity and calling in your creation.
And we are so often prone to seize that for ourselves.
Sometimes intentionally, sometimes unintentionally.
And God, these screens that sit in our pockets, they become accelerators for whatever is in our hearts.
And so my prayer for all of us throughout this series is that as we step back from our technology,
as we think about the ways in which we interact with our technology,
it would just be revealing to us what is actually true in our hearts.
Not what we say is true in our hearts when we show up to church on Sunday with our nice dress clothes on,
but what is actually true in our hearts when nobody's around, when nobody's looking.
And God, that this would lead us to re-surrender to your wisdom,
for your glory, for our good, for the good of our neighbor.
It's in Jesus' name I pray. Amen.
I gave my friend Brian here a cue to come up way too early,
so hopefully his fingers are not cramping at this point.
But I asked Brian to come up before we conclude and just lead us in a few courses of,
"Lord, I need you." I asked him to make it plural.
This is something we do often to make this language corporate as we sing.
So I'd love for us to stand and reflect on this idea that there is a temptation to believe that we can get Eden-like circumstances apart from God,
but it never, it always over-promises and under-delivers.
And the reality of our situation is we need the Lord.
We need His wisdom, not just individually, but corporately.
And we don't just need it every Sunday morning, but we need it every moment of every day.
So let's worship together as we get ready to head out.